Privacy policy
==============

Simply put: Buttondown doesn't do anything weird with your data
---------------------------------------------------------------

**Last updated October 20, 2019**

Thank you for choosing to be part of our community at Buttondown, LLC (“**Company**”, “**we**”, “**us**”, or “**our**”). We are committed to protecting your personal information and your right to privacy. If you have any questions or concerns about our policy, or our practices with regards to your personal information, please contact us at justin@buttondown.email.

When you visit our website buttondown.email, and use our services, you trust us with your personal information. We take your privacy very seriously. In this privacy policy, we seek to explain to you in the clearest way possible what information we collect, how we use it and what rights you have in relation to it. We hope you take some time to read through it carefully, as it is important. If there are any terms in this privacy policy that you do not agree with, please discontinue use of our Sites and our services.

This privacy policy applies to all information collected through our website (such as buttondown.email), and/or any related services, sales, marketing or events (we refer to them collectively in this privacy policy as the "**Services**").

**Please read this privacy policy carefully as it will help you make informed decisions about sharing your personal information with us.**

### 1\. What we collect

**Personal information you disclose to us**

_**In Short:**_ _We collect personal information that you provide to us such as name, address, contact information, passwords and security data, and payment information._

We collect personal information that you voluntarily provide to us when registering at the Services expressing an interest in obtaining information about us or our products and services, when participating in activities on the Services or otherwise contacting us.

The personal information that we collect depends on the context of your interactions with us and the Services, the choices you make and the products and features you use. The personal information we collect can include the following:

**Publicly Available Personal Information.** We collect email addresses, business email, social media, and other similar data. **Credentials.** We collect passwords, password hints, and similar security information used for authentication and account access. **Payment Data.** We collect data necessary to process your payment if you make purchases, such as your payment instrument number (such as a credit card number), and the security code associated with your payment instrument. All payment data is stored by Stripe. You may find their privacy policy link(s) here: stripe.com.

All personal information that you provide to us must be true, complete and accurate, and you must notify us of any changes to such personal information.

**Information automatically collected**

_**In Short:**_ _Some information – such as IP address and/or browser and device characteristics – is collected automatically when you visit our Services._

We automatically collect certain information when you visit, use or navigate the Services. This information does not reveal your specific identity (like your name or contact information) but may include device and usage information, such as your IP address, browser and device characteristics, operating system, language preferences, referring URLs, device name, country, location, information about how and when you use our Services and other technical information. This information is primarily needed to maintain the security and operation of our Services, and for our internal analytics and reporting purposes.

Like many businesses, we also collect information through cookies and similar technologies.

**Online Identifiers.** We collect devices, tools and protocols, such as IP (Internet Protocol) addresses, cookie identifiers, or others such as the ones used for analytics and marketing, and other similar data.

### 2\. How we use it

_**In Short:**_ _We process your information for purposes based on legitimate business interests, the fulfillment of our contract with you, compliance with our legal obligations, and/or your consent._

We use personal information collected via our Services for a variety of business purposes described below. We process your personal information for these purposes in reliance on our legitimate business interests, in order to enter into or perform a contract with you, with your consent, and/or for compliance with our legal obligations. We indicate the specific processing grounds we rely on next to each purpose listed below.

We use the information we collect or receive:

* **To send you marketing and promotional communications.** We and/or our third party marketing partners may use the personal information you send to us for our marketing purposes, if this is in accordance with your marketing preferences. You can opt-out of our marketing emails at any time (see the "[WHAT ARE YOUR PRIVACY RIGHTS](#privacyrights)" below).
* **To send administrative information to you.** We may use your personal information to send you product, service and new feature information and/or information about changes to our terms, conditions, and policies.
* **Request Feedback.** We may use your information to request feedback and to contact you about your use of our Services.
* **To protect our Services.** We may use your information as part of our efforts to keep our Services safe and secure (for example, for fraud monitoring and prevention).
* **To manage user accounts**. We may use your information for the purposes of managing our account and keeping it in working order.
* **To deliver services to the user.** We may use your information to provide you with the requested service.

### 3\. Who we share it with

_**In Short:**_ _We only share information with your consent, to comply with laws, to provide you with services, to protect your rights, or to fulfill business obligations._

We may process or share data based on the following legal basis:

* **Consent:** We may process your data if you have given us specific consent to use your personal information in a specific purpose.
* **Legitimate Interests:** We may process your data when it is reasonably necessary to achieve our legitimate business interests.
* **Performance of a Contract:** Where we have entered into a contract with you, we may process your personal information to fulfill the terms of our contract.
* **Legal Obligations:** We may disclose your information where we are legally required to do so in order to comply with applicable law, governmental requests, a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process, such as in response to a court order or a subpoena (including in response to public authorities to meet national security or law enforcement requirements).
* **Vital Interests:** We may disclose your information where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding potential violations of our policies, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person and illegal activities, or as evidence in litigation in which we are involved.

More specifically, we may need to process your data or share your personal information in the following situations:

* **Business Transfers.** We may share or transfer your information in connection with, or during negotiations of, any merger, sale of company assets, financing, or acquisition of all or a portion of our business to another company.
* **Third-Party Advertisers.** We may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit the Services. These companies may use information about your visits to our Website(s) and other websites that are contained in web cookies and other tracking technologies in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.

### 4\. Cookies and tracking

_**In Short:**_ _We may use cookies and other tracking technologies to collect and store your information._

We may use cookies and similar tracking technologies (like web beacons and pixels) to access or store information. Specific information about how we use such technologies and how you can refuse certain cookies is set out in our [Cookie Policy](https://buttondown.email/legal/cookies).

**5\. Data retention**

_**In Short:**_ _We keep your information for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this privacy policy unless otherwise required by law._

We will only keep your personal information for as long as it is necessary for the purposes set out in this privacy policy, unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law (such as tax, accounting or other legal requirements). No purpose in this policy will require us keeping your personal information for longer than the period of time in which users have an account with us.

When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymize it, or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible.

### 6\. Keeping your data safe

_**In Short:**_ _We aim to protect your personal information through a system of organizational and technical security measures._

We have implemented appropriate technical and organizational security measures designed to protect the security of any personal information we process. However, please also remember that we cannot guarantee that the internet itself is 100% secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal information, transmission of personal information to and from our Services is at your own risk. You should only access the services within a secure environment.

### 7\. Collecting information from minors

_**In Short:**_ _We do not knowingly collect data from or market to children under 18 years of age._

We do not knowingly solicit data from or market to children under 18 years of age. By using the Services, you represent that you are at least 18 or that you are the parent or guardian of such a minor and consent to such minor dependent’s use of the Services. If we learn that personal information from users less than 18 years of age has been collected, we will deactivate the account and take reasonable measures to promptly delete such data from our records. If you become aware of any data we have collected from children under age 18, please contact us at justin@buttondown.email.

### 8\. Your privacy rights

_**In Short:**_ _In some regions, such as the European Economic Area, you have rights that allow you greater access to and control over your personal information. You may review, change, or terminate your account at any time._

In some regions (like the European Economic Area), you have certain rights under applicable data protection laws. These may include the right (i) to request access and obtain a copy of your personal information, (ii) to request rectification or erasure; (iii) to restrict the processing of your personal information; and (iv) if applicable, to data portability. In certain circumstances, you may also have the right to object to the processing of your personal information. To make such a request, please use the [contact details](#contact) provided below. We will consider and act upon any request in accordance with applicable data protection laws.

If we are relying on your consent to process your personal information, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. Please note however that this will not affect the lawfulness of the processing before its withdrawal.

If you are resident in the European Economic Area and you believe we are unlawfully processing your personal information, you also have the right to complain to your local data protection supervisory authority. You can find their contact details here: [http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index\_en.htm](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index_en.htm).

**Account Information**

If you would at any time like to review or change the information in your account or terminate your account, you can:

* Log into your account settings and update your user account.

Upon your request to terminate your account, we will deactivate or delete your account and information from our active databases. However, some information may be retained in our files to prevent fraud, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigations, enforce our Terms of Use and/or comply with legal requirements.

**Cookies and similar technologies:** Most Web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove cookies and to reject cookies. If you choose to remove cookies or reject cookies, this could affect certain features or services of our Services. To opt-out of interest-based advertising by advertisers on our Services visit [http://www.aboutads.info/choices/](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

**Opting out of email marketing:** You can unsubscribe from our marketing email list at any time by clicking on the unsubscribe link in the emails that we send or by contacting us using the details provided below. You will then be removed from the marketing email list – however, we will still need to send you service-related emails that are necessary for the administration and use of your account. To otherwise opt-out, you may:

* Access your account settings and update preferences.

### 9\. Data breaches

A privacy breach occurs when there is unauthorized access to or collection, use, disclosure or disposal of personal information. You will be notified about data breaches when Buttondown, LLC believes you are likely to be at risk of serious harm. For example, a data breach may be likely to result in serious financial harm or harm to your mental or physical well-being. In the event that Buttondown, LLC becomes aware of a security breach which has resulted or may result in unauthorized access, use or disclosure of personal information Buttondown, LLC will promptly investigate the matter and notify the applicable Supervisory Authority not later than 72 hours after having become aware of it, unless the personal data breach is unlikely to result in a risk to the rights and freedoms of natural persons.

### 10\. Do-not-track features

Most web browsers and some mobile operating systems and mobile applications include a Do-Not-Track (“DNT”) feature or setting you can activate to signal your privacy preference not to have data about your online browsing activities monitored and collected. No uniform technology standard for recognizing and implementing DNT signals has been finalized. As such, we do not currently respond to DNT browser signals or any other mechanism that automatically communicates your choice not to be tracked online. If a standard for online tracking is adopted that we must follow in the future, we will inform you about that practice in a revised version of this privacy policy.

### 11\. California residents

_**In Short:**_ \_Yes, if you are a resident of California, you are granted specific rights regarding access to your personal information. \_

California Civil Code Section 1798.83, also known as the “Shine The Light” law, permits our users who are California residents to request and obtain from us, once a year and free of charge, information about categories of personal information (if any) we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes and the names and addresses of all third parties with which we shared personal information in the immediately preceding calendar year. If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please submit your request in writing to us using the contact information provided below.

If you are under 18 years of age, reside in California, and have a registered account with the Services, you have the right to request removal of unwanted data that you publicly post on the Services. To request removal of such data, please contact us using the contact information provided below, and include the email address associated with your account and a statement that you reside in California. We will make sure the data is not publicly displayed on the Services, but please be aware that the data may not be completely or comprehensively removed from our systems.

### 12\. Updates to this policy

_**In Short:**_ _Yes, we will update this policy as necessary to stay compliant with relevant laws._

We may update this privacy policy from time to time. The updated version will be indicated by an updated “Revised” date and the updated version will be effective as soon as it is accessible. If we make material changes to this privacy policy, we may notify you either by prominently posting a notice of such changes or by directly sending you a notification. We encourage you to review this privacy policy frequently to be informed of how we are protecting your information.

Contact Us
----------

If you have questions or comments about this policy, you may contact our Data Protection Officer (DPO), Justin Duke, by email at justin@buttondown.email, or by post to:

Buttondown, LLC  
Justin Duke  
2917 W Grace St.  
Richmond VA, 23221  
United States

What customers say about Buttondown
-----------------------------------

Buttondown's customer service: NEXT LEVEL AMAZING.

James Whatley  
Senior Strategy Director, The LEGO Group

So far I like Buttondown because it's felt SO MUCH SIMPLER to use its backend than any other similar system I've used before.

May Peterson  
Author, The Sacred Dark

Doesn't matter if you're sending out irregular updates to a few dozen friends, or marketing your business to a thousand recipients. It is absolutely a joy to use. The documentation is great. And Justin provides the best support I have ever encountered. Amazon isn't the world's most customer-centric company, Buttondown is.

Tilde Lowengrimm  
Head of Strategy, Red Queen Dynamics

I made the transition from MailerLite and I have no regrets. I also like that Buttondown focuses on the essentials by design and keeps me grounded and centered on what really matters.

Arthur Cendrier  
Author, Thoughtful Inquiry

Overall, Buttondown has been terrific to work with and I recommend them for anybody who's thinking of starting a newsletter or moving over like I did.

Andy Magnusson  
Customer Engineering Leader

Wanna know how good Buttondown as a product experience is? I upgraded to Basic before sending the first email, and then upgraded again two days later.

Zak El Fassi  
Founder, Zaigood Labs

Mailchimp lost me due to their inferior product and the nightmarish merry-go-around experience with their overseas support team. Buttondown won me over with their superior product and second to none customer service.

[Sav Tripodi  
CEO, Sanico Software](https://www.sanico.com.au/blog/buttondown-a-founder-leading-by-example-with-superior-customer-service/)

Your support is amazing and I deeply appreciate how available and helpful you are. I LOVE being able to turn tracking pixels off. I didn't even realize this was an option when I signed up and am SO HAPPY to not track people.

[Andrea Mignolo  
Method & Matter](https://methodandmatter.com/)

I'm also impressed with how responsive you are, and how you directly answer customers. Makes it really clear that signing up for your service was a good decision.

[Nicole Tietz-Sokolskaya  
Software engineer and writer](https://tietz.social/@nicole)

Very happy with Buttondown, works smoothly, it's very configurable and I love the minimalist design of the UI. It makes me focus on my writing. Plus, I'm super happy to support independent software and I should mention - the support I receive whenever I have a question is warm and quick :)

Martina Pugliese  
Data scientist and storyteller

I just tested the RSS to Email feature for one of my blogs and it was incredibly easy to set up. It took me about 30 mins to figure out the same feature in Mailchimp.

Nicolas Bernadowitsch  
Blogger

This long weekend I fulfilled a long-standing promise to myself to switch my RSS-to-email provider from Mailchimp to Buttondown, and it’s been such a great experience. It’s cheaper, more flexible, less cluttered, and it’s run by Justin Duke who is just delightful and answered a bunch of my questions over the weekend (even though I asked him to please not!).

Rian van der Merwe  
Director of Product at PagerDuty

I've been wrangling half a dozen tools to get my stuff up and running recently, almost all of which had some hiccup. Buttondown had zero. It did everything I expected and needed the first time.

[Catherine Cusick  
Self-Employed FAQ](https://www.selfemployedfaq.com/)

I, like almost everyone else I've seen talk about Buttondown, am IMMENSELY happy and impressed with your customer service. It turns out we can have nice things, which is really refreshing.

[Ed Yong  
Staff writer, The Atlantic](https://www.theatlantic.com/author/ed-yong/)

Email makes the world go ‘round, and Buttondown is how I manage it all for my keyboard projects.

[Tim van Damme  
Founder, MVKB](https://mvkb.com/)

It's a truth, that should be more universally acknowledged, that Buttondown is the best newsletter software. Simple, does exactly what it sets out to do, and reasonably priced.

[Noel Welsh  
Founder, Inner Product](https://noelwelsh.com/landing/about/)

Buttondown is the perfect fit for my headless newsletter use case. And I contacted support with some specific requests and Justin responded within 30 minutes with great answers and a nice pinch of charm.

[Sam Roberts  
Software engineer, Tamr](https://samgqroberts.com/)

Hands down the easiest way to run a newsletter - and the free version is generous!

Javeed Khatree  
SEO expert

With API and Markdown support, you can build workflows that make it so easy to write.

[Westley Winks  
Peace Corps](https://westleywinks.com/)

I’ve never enjoyed writing newsletters as much as I do with Buttondown.

Kevin Lewis  
You Got This!

Buttondown remains the easiest thing I use regularly, and I am grateful for that.

Casey  
Journalist

It's a humble app doing a common job but with end users in mind.

Si Jobling  
Engineering Manager

Buttondown has been an amazing experience for me. The service is constantly being improved and customer service is the best. My newsletter with Buttondown has grown from a fairly small list to over 15,000 subscribers, and it hasn't broken a sweat yet.

Cassidy Williams  
CTO, Contenda

I switched over to Buttondown from Mailchimp because of the difficulty I had with Mailchimp's campaigns, so Buttondown's easy and user-friendly system has been a genuine breath of fresh air.

Jessi Eoin  
Illustrator + Comic Artist

You’ve truly built a great product that I feel good about using (vs a monopoly from our tech overlords).

Rachel  
2030 Camp

I love how personal Buttondown feels, especially compared to Mailchimp, Convertkit, and services like that.

Simen Strøm Braaten  
Designer

This product has been exactly what I’ve needed!

[Nathan Bird  
Podcast host, Chattanooga Civics](http://chattanoogacivics.com/)

It's already so refreshing compared to the mega companies.

Casey Watts  
Author, Debugging Your Brain

Definitely will be using for the foreseeable future. It’s a great service and I feel well cared for. Thank you!

Phoebe Sinclair  
Author

I’m a sucker for elegant UI and I really love your site, but above that I think your product has so much value for so many different people. I’m not a coder, I’m only familiar with the bare basics, but I was able to figure out and utilise Buttondown quickly.

Claudia Nathan  
Founder, The Repository

The killer feature for me: Buttondown will take an RSS feed then automatically slurp up the content (in their words) and then send it to our subscribers. Job done. They seem like a good company too, so I’d say this is a winner.

Andy Bell  
Founder, Set Studio

As a recent user of Buttondown, they are super on the ball. A week ago I discovered a security vulnerability and reported it on Friday afternoon. They acknowledged and fixed it in under two hours. On a Friday night! Talk about going above and beyond for your users!

[Predrag Gruevski  
Principal Engineer, Kensho](https://predr.ag/blog/)

Well may I just say your support experience is already approximately 1 billion times better than ConvertKit. Excited to be switching!

Michael J. Metts  
Author, Writing is Designing

Privacy focused sending and sign up form; lets me focus on writing - editor is "just" markdown; simple, elegant design template looks like a blog post; the founder is amazing - he's helped with every question I've had, even outside of Buttondown.

Joe Masilotti  
Founder, RailsDevs

We need more nice and professional services like yours on the web.

Tobias Horvath  
Designer and developer

No one is paying me to say this, but I love @buttondown so far for my lil newsletter. It’s so smart, simple, and attractive (and to my knowledge, not actively anti-trans!). Customer service is also legitimately excellent.

Julie Kliegman  
Copy chief, Sports Illustrated

I love it! It lets me breathe, not compete as I write with other writers.

Devin Kate Pope  
Writer and editor

It’s a pleasure working with you. Thank you! (And what a contrast with Mailchimp, where I spent two weeks and a dozen of emails trying find out why our form goes down sometimes (only sometimes), and never really got a real answer.)

Anton Sotkov  
Software Engineer, IA

Buttondown exemplifies how I wish most software worked, and I hope to achieve a similar thing with the software I develop in the future.

Matt Favero  
Software engineer

It feels incomparably good to be able to email just like a guy named Justin when you have a @buttondown question 15 minutes before you’re about to blast a Geistlist email. (Not a guarantee but wow this guy is human-level good.)

Jacob Ford  
Designer About Town

Enter Buttondown, Justin Duke’s lovely little newsletter tool. It’s small, elegant, and integrates well. And it is also eminently affordable.

Will Buckingham  
Author

Your settings page is a joy to use and everything about Buttondown makes me happy.

Gareth Jelley  
Magazine editor

have been on Buttondown for ~18 months and I can't recommend it enough.

Elizabeth Minkel  
Podcast host

You really do make ALL other customer service look terrible by comparison.

Chris Mead  
Improv teacher

There is a caring person on the other side of this software, which is one of the things I like the most about Buttondown.

Keith Calder  
Film & TV Producer

I’d also like to add that @buttondown is an absolute joy to use. Hats off, Justin!

Elliot Jay Stocks  
Creative Director, Google Fonts

Shoutout to @buttondown and @jmduke for building an amazing bootstrapped product for newsletters, all while being very open to feedback and connecting directly with customers 🙏 Easily one of the most enjoyable product experiences I've had.

Den Delimarsky  
Head of Ecosystem, Netlify

if you are looking for "newsletter tool for hackers" i tentatively believe the answer is @buttondown full api, compose in markdown, good docs for setting up domain auth, simple subscribe form HTML that you style yourself (or not)

Brian David Hall  
Author, Your Website Sucks

I really like @buttondown as a blogging platform, it has the simplicity of Substack but the corporate culture is less toxic.

Chad Loder  
Extremism researcher

I worked with @buttondown and asked for some new payment support beyond the supporter single tier / pay-what-you-want options. Justin was great and built it in just a couple days.

Dan Hon  
Author & consultant

I write nonfiction and I use @buttondown buttondown.email/Changeset - indie, GREAT personal customer support, very nice default styling, all the options I want including ones to protect my readers' privacy

Sumana Harihareswara  
Open source maintainer

I use @buttondown because it does exactly what I need (manage subscribers and send markdown emails), not more and not less 👍 As a bonus it's made by an indie dev which I love!

Max Stober  
Founder, GraphCDN

If you’re considering running an email newsletter, or if you already run one and are considering a change of provider, I highly recommend @buttondownemail. Super-easy app, very fair pricing with a generous free tier, and exemplary support. 💯

Peter Gasston  
Technologist and speaker

imo @buttondown is easily one of the best-designed services i’ve used in recent years, if you have a substack you should really consider switching!

Kabir Goel  
Engineer, Cal

Thanks for getting me excited about email newsletters again.

Garrick van Buren  

I'm very thrilled that I can just write in Markdown without having to deal with email builders and all that crap.

Parham Doustdar  

Thanks again for all the help! You’ve really turned something super complex into something super easy – sending new issues is as simple as firing off a text message.

Kartik Chaturvedi  

Thanks for creating a simple way for people who want to, like, put words in a hole and have it sent to people... I am just thankful that something just nice and human exists on the internet.

Emmanuel Quartey  

I tried 3 other newsletter services today and I felt like wanting to rip my hair out. They were all painfully slow. I'm so glad I found Buttondown.

Mohamed Elbadwihi  

I’ve found Buttondown to be a great fit for my workflow and have been delighted by all of Justin’s thoughtful features and improvements to the product.

Michael Lee  

Like seriously, so many lovely little easter eggs in one could-be-boring service.

Alexandra Muck  

I just switched over from Tinyletter and I'm really excited to have found a place to host my tiny newsletter that doesn't seem like it's assuming everyone sending newsletters is an email marketer / growth hacker.

Tessa Alexanian  

I'm in love with the simplicity of Buttondown.

I’ve used similar tools in the past and Buttondown is by far the simplest to use and most promising.

Fabrizio Rinaldi  

Thank you for creating such a simple and brilliant tool. I’ve just signed up and the experience has been smooth and painless (the docs are great too!)

Oliver Holms  

As a developer who has hated every email system I've ever used this is so nice.

Drew Hornbein  

I wish I still wrote a newsletter just so I could use buttondown again. It’s like that.

Steven Kornweiss  

No credit card required. Only pay for what you use. Cancel anytime.

© 2024 Buttondown. All rights reserved; have a lovely day.
